<page title="Helpers">
  <para>Miscellaneous helper scripts and resources used to build the other projects.
  The main components of the project are settings for the Eclipse IDE, resources for
  creating Javadoc, and some JUnit test helpers.</para>
  <section title="Eclipse settings">
    <para>All Java source code in these projects has been autoformatted using an
    Eclipse plugin. The settings in <code>eclipse-java-formatting.xml</code> can be
    imported and, for example, used on save to maintain code consistency.</para>
  </section>
  <section title="Javadoc stylesheet">
    <para>Including Java code fragments in Javadoc comments is a useful way to
    explain and exemplify the classes and methods being documented. The
    <code>javadoc-stylesheet.css</code> resource is a default JDK 1.7 stylesheet
    with some additions to assist in formatting such code samples in a manner
    similar to many popular IDEs.</para>
    <para>A <code>pre</code> tag is used to contain code. This allows for appropriate
    indentation to be used. Additional <code>span</code> tags are used to specify
    keywords (<code>k</code>), identifiers (<code>i</code>), comments
    (<code>c</code>) and literals (<code>l</code>). For example:</para>
    <para type="java">
      <javadoc>
        <li>Lorum ipsem, etc, foo:</li>
        <li/>
        <li>&lt;pre class="code java"&gt;</li>
        <indent>
          <li>&lt;span class="k"&gt;public class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="i"&gt;Foo&lt;/span&gt; {</li>
          <indent>
            <li/>
            <li>&lt;span class="k"&gt;private int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="i"&gt;_bar&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class="i"&gt;1234&lt;/span&gt;;</li>
            <li/>
            <li>&lt;span class="c"&gt;// ... etc&lt;/span&gt;</li>
            <li/>
          </indent>
          <li>}</li>
        </indent>
        <li>&lt;/pre&gt;</li>
      </javadoc>
      <kw>public</kw><t> </t><id>something</id><t> ()</t>
      <block>
        <linecomment>...</linecomment>
      </block>
    </para>
    <para>Would render with appropriate syntax highlighting defined by the
    stylesheet. The styles are divided to give a generic <code>code</code> class
    which defines some common formatting and then a more specific <code>java</code>
    class. This pattern then allows code examples to be given in alternative
    languages such as C++.</para>
  </section>
  <section title="JUnit">
    <para>The unit testing framework of choice for these projects is JUnit. Some
    additional rules and static helper methods are defined here for convenience.
    More details can be found in the Javadocs.</para>
  </section>
  <links>
    <link title="Junit helper Javadoc" href="junit/0.1.0/javadoc"/>
    <link title="Maven artifact" href="maven.html"/>
    <link title="Source code" href="http://github.com/beerdragon/helpers"/>
  </links>
</page>
